lason D. Rodis

Research Associate / Software Engineer linkedin:jasrodis

Profile

An ambitious and dynamic software engineer with background in research and over four years of experience who works to high personal standards. Self-motivated and confident working, either on own initiative or as an integral team member.

Work Experience

| 2016-Present | Software Engineering Fellow CERN, <u>cern.ch</u> Beams Department, Beam Instrumentation, Software Section |
|--------------|--|
| 2015-2016 | Software Engineering Intern, CERN, <u>cern.ch</u> Beams Department, Beam Instrumentation, Software Section |
| 2014-2015 | Research Associate / Software Engineer, Scan Group, scan.di.uoa.gr Department of Informatics & Telecommunications, University of Athens. |
| 2013-2014 | Collaboration with Bentley Motors Infotainment . |
| 2011-Present | Freelance website developer and administrator. |
| 2011-2012 | Tech support Agent [ADSL/ISDN], <i>Hellenic Telecommunications Organisation S.A</i> <u>ote.gr</u> |

Education & Training

| 2016 | CERN Accelerator School, Communication Training |
|-----------|--|
| 2015 | FESA Hands-on Training, Introduction to MEAN.js framework, CERN, Security training |
| 2009-2016 | BSc Department of Informatics & Telecommunications , <i>University of Athens, GPA 7.0/10.0 - 240 ECTS</i> |
| 2009 | Graduated from "Lycée Léonin", Greek-French High school. |

Projects & Services

CERN Beams Instrumentation Software Portal

Web application used for delivering and launching ExpertGuis and documenting FESA Classes Based on Maven, MySQL, Spring Boot, AngularJS, Websockets, ElasticSearch.

LHC Feedback Dashboard

An expert monitoring suite for the LHC beam-based feedbacks. Based on FESA C++, Maven, JavaFX

JavaFX DataViewer

JavaFX-based data visualisation prototype library, *github link*. Based on Maven, JavaFX, Jetty, WebSockets, plotly.js

Scan Group FIspace, fispace.eu, bitbucket.org/fispace (Open-source Project)

FIspace is a social network platform for business-to-business (B2B) collaboration. **Web Application** - Front/Back-end Web Developer with the latest technologies. Based on Maven, Spring MVC, Atmosphere Framework, jQuery, AngularJS, Bower, Grunt and keycloak.

Diploma Thesis based on **Univerself**, *univerself*-project.eu

Thesis Title: Adapting Policy-based Management of Future Networks using Collaborative Fil-

tering Techniques.

Based on Java Swing, Web services REST, owl, rdf, MySQL.

Bentley Motors **EQtoolHelper**

Data analysis software package of the "NAIM for Bentley" audio amplifier.

Based on Java SE, Swing, JAXB.

Freelance Various websites developed with CMS platforms, JHipster stack

IT Skills & Expertise

Languages Java, C, C++, Python*, Javascript

Java EE, Spring, Swing, JavaFX, Maven, Atmosphere Web Html5, CSS3, jQuery, AngularJS, NodeJS* WebSockets

Databases HSQL-MySQL, NoSQL*

Various Wordpress/Joomla, Matlab, OpenGL*, SEO, git, mercurial, bash, SCRUM

OS Linux, OS X, Windows

(*familiar with)

Volunteering

TEDxCERN

Official CERN Guide

Languages

Greek Native

English C2 - Excellent knowledge.

French Sorbonne 2 (C2 equivalent) Excellent knowledge.

Interests

Music Production, Travelling, Snowboarding, Camping, Hiking, Blockchain

Publications & Conferences

[3] lason Rodis, Athanasios Topaloudis, 'Common Standards for JavaFX GUI Development and its application to the Renovation of the CERN Beam Instrumentation Software Portal and Delivery Mechanism', for the 16th International Conference on Accelerator and Large Experimental Physics Control Systems, ICALEPCS 2017

[2] Diogo Alves, **Iason Rodis**, Stephen Jackson, 'A monitoring system for the beam-based feed-backs in the LHC', for the Real Time Conference (RT), 2016 IEEE-NPSS.

[1] R. Arapoglou, I. Rodis, P. Magdalinos, N. Alonistioti, 'Adapting Policy-based Management of Future Networks using Collaborative Filtering Techniques', for the 19th IEEE International Workshop on Computer Aided Modelling and Design of Communication Links and Networks.